# Preshita Kargutkar

A/302 Kavya Residency, Anand Nagar, Kasarwadavali, Ghodbunder Rd. Thane(W). 400615.

**Mail ID** - kargutkarpk@gmail.com

**Contact No.** - 9987919121

# **SUMMARY:**

Motivated and dedicated professional, critical thinker and problem solver with 13+ years of experience in corporate world. Worked as Logistic executive and planning executive in **Asian Paints Ltd**. for 11 yrs. Seeking a challenging and rewarding position in reputed company.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Logistics Executive (Supply Chain – Outbound Logistics) - Jul 2017 to Jan 2020 Asian Paints Ltd.

- Freight-Supplementary Bill Clearance & resolution of payment related issues with stakeholders.
- Market Truck Placement, Quotations, Freight rate updations, Service Entry Closure
   & Debit Note Raising, Annexure Management.
- Pending /Partial GR Tracking & Closure, Revision of Standard Time basis actuals.
- Supplier Portal Enhancement & Issue Resolution.
- New Transporter Sourcing (Database, Introduction, Legal Agreement Management)
- Analysis of Daily Tracking sheet.
- Scheduling & arranging Negotiation meetings with transporters.

#### **Payment**

- DTS Tracking and closure (Interaction with SSC, Transporters, Plants/OPCs, Depots, Purchase Product team)
- Wrong Service entry closure
- Hundi Related Issue Resolution with SSC/Plant, e-Hundi conversion
- New transporters payment mode submitting e-payment declaration and cancel cheque to SSC.

# **PSE**

- Open Shipments tracking and closure
- Service Entries tracking and closure
- Monitoring old pending service entry closure fortnightly
- Follow up with sending location for closure

#### Placement

- Placement Cell Management(Performance tracking & reviews) Placement Cell PO/Invoice processing.
- Default Waivers and Debit Note Raising for Defaults, Ordering Hygiene and Tracking.

# Reports

- Monthly Reports on Cost Per Ton, Avg KM, Rail -road Proportion tracker
- Purchase order generation for the whole year negotiated rates.
- Underweight Value Impact Analysis.
- NDC & related follow ups

# Executive Planner (Supply Chain - Materials) Asian Paints Ltd.

- Jan 2009 to Jun 2017
- Plan correction at the start of every FN based on demand, plant constraints and supply constraints (RM+PM)
- Generate RM & PM demand based on the Paint plans at Unit level and upload the same in system for Purchase team
- Preparation and monitoring of RM & PM coverage at units, anticipation of issues based on supplies and consumption. Also, have preventive & corrective action plan in place.
- Monitor production with the plant at Streams/Products/Pack Level
- Generation and circulation of daily reports to plant and team for easy monitoring of health of the system and daily deliveries along with on-going updates on issues
- Interface with purchase and plant teams, highlight and resolve issues related to the same
- Report the production performance and tie up with SKU variance
- Generate, record and circulate weekly, FN and monthly reports for production across the organization
- Check for feasibility of plans loaded with plants based on capacity constraints in emulsion, resin, manpower and other resources POV
- Support for definitions of any new products/shade/SKUs introduced in the plants before the start of FN level
- Facilitate delivery of non-inventoried items and Direct Sales orders
- Priority SKU management among distribution and plants to ensure critical SKUs are serviced on time
- Cater to export requirement for Asian Paints overseas units among plants and IBU supply chain
- AIG management by balancing effective material utilization and optimal production scheduling

- Understand the dynamic production scheduling of plants, align the same to demand and act as a bridge between Supply chain and manufacturing
- Identification and implementation of development projects for automation, avoiding NVA and various other developmental activities.
- Working on reports
- YTD SKU Variance
- Co-ordination with Distribution, Purchase (RM,PM) Planning execution team, New products team and other units for their respective input for RM and PM requirement.
- Plan Corrections for fortnight and for month.
- Packing material planning and pure planning for future month
- Non-Inventory requirement fulfilling.

MIS Executive - Jun 2007 to Dec 2008 ICICI Bank Ltd.

• Co-ordinating for execution of MIS of All India level for Branch Managers.

# **Academic Qualification:**

**B.Sc.** (IT) in the year 2006 with 62% from Thakur college of Science and Commerce (Mumbai University).

Higher Secondary School (HSC) (Science Stream) in the year 2003 with 50% from Nirmala Memorial College of Science and Commerce (Maharashtra State Board of secondary and higher secondary Examination).

**Secondary School (S.S.C)** in the Year 2000 with 74% from **Swami Vivekanand Vidyamandir** (Maharashtra State Board of secondary and higher secondary Examination).

# **Computer Awareness & Skills set:**

- Good hand on experience in SAP, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook)
- Strong analytical and communication skills
- Ability to multi-task
- Adapts quickly to new and changing technology
- Excellent time management

# **Personal Profile:**

Date of Birth - 23rd Oct 1984
Contact No. - 9987919121
Gender - Female
Marital status - Married
Nationality - Indian

Languages - Marathi, English and Hindi

I hereby declare that the above information furnished by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: - MUMBAI PRESHITA KARGUTKAR